# **Joshua Robins**

E-mail: joshuazrobins@gmail.com Phone: (818) 257-0963

# Summary

Product leader with 2-3 years of experience strategically building and managing software applications using lean / agile principles, with an emphasis on user-centered design. A technologist at heart, a creative problem-solver, and a servant leader with experience leading cross-functional teams.

• Co-founded the Food Oasis LA nonprofit in 2016 and led its consumer-facing application. Orchestrated its acquisition to Youth Policy Institute in 2018.

#### **Experience**

#### LA Counts

# Los Angeles, CA May 2018 – present

# Associate Project Manager / Product Manager

- Drove adoption of new project management tools and overhauled its Google Analytics setup to report more thoughtful metrics and data insights.
- Led the product team through design strategy and design sprints, handing off wireframes and high-fidelity mockups to developers.
- Conducted user testing sessions, gathering feedback and insights to drive informed decisions in each iteration of the design.
- Supported senior leadership in running weekly sync-ups with our developers, prioritizing features, and organizing the product roadmap / backlog.
- Engaged with external partners and stakeholders across government agencies, nonprofits, and universities.

#### Food Oasis LA

# Product Manager / Co-founder

Los Angeles, CA May 2016 – Jan 2018

- Led the shaping and defining of our shared product vision. Triage and prioritize features for the roadmap and backlog.
- Led a diverse group of volunteers to design and build an MVP within 4 months. Delivered 2 months ahead of schedule (6-month objective).
- · Conducted weekly user interviews and testing sessions to ensure a user-centered focus in each sprint.
- The team was interviewed for a CNN.com series discussing the problem of food deserts while promoting our civic-focused product.

## CTDI

# Software Engineer

Fontana, CA Feb 2013 – Feb 2018

- Full-stack web development for the core product used in quality-control operations. Experienced in JavaScript, HTML, REST APIs, and Oracle / SQL Server databases.
- Communicated and built shared understanding with senior leadership of a long-standing data-reporting
  problem among multiple facilities' operations. Led the design and development of a product that
  increased reporting efficiency by 93% and removed all possibilities of human error. Drove its adoption
  across 20 facilities and 3 customer programs.

### **Activities**

#### Hack for LA

# Brigade Leader / Product Manager

Los Angeles, CA Sep 2017 – present

- Lead, mentor, and organize a community of civic tech enthusiasts as we strategize, design, and build digital products to best serve the people of Los Angeles.
- Provide pro bono tech consulting services for City of Los Angeles, LA County, and local nonprofits.
- The brigade was presented with certificates of excellence by the Los Angeles City Council for its work in civic tech within the community.

#### Education

## University of California, Los Angeles

B.S. Electrical Engineering – 2007–2011